you know for any of you Google hackers
there I'm sure this guy went through and
totally milked all of this and you
should definitely not look for any of
the ones that he missed using appscript
and you should also definitely not diff
the appscript docs to make sure when new
functions are added that you can't be
abused to do something similar I think
that's probably a waste of time because
this guy definitely found everything as
all testers
[Music]
do best path of Ving when you can just
you know critical thing
[Music]
right yeah
dude sup hackers so zero trust world
just happened and threat Locker dropped
some pretty cool stuff my favorite of
the bunch was threat Locker Cloud
control and I'll tell you why okay so
when you're trying to hack an
organization nowadays what's kind of
like the go-to approach well for most
it's going to be set up evil engine X
and send out a bunch of fishing emails
right that way you don't have to worry
about um two-factor authentication or
anything like that because evil engine X
is just going to let them put in their
password their TFA and then just hand
you back a session token to interact
with Microsoft 365 so threat Locker
realized this was a problem and so what
they decided to do was build Cloud
control which uses the threat Locker
agent to sync into Microsoft cloud
conditional access a list of approved IP
addresses from which a user can connect
right so so then an attacker gets that
token that they stole by evil engine X
they try to use it to interact with
Microsoft 365 and boom they're burned
because they're not coming from a
permitted Network and they lose access
it's pretty sick it's a great solution
to the problem so definitely check it
out threat Locker Cloud control all
right back to the
show ladies and gentlemen boys and girls
hackers this kind of week is the week
that makes the podcaster let me tell you
our boy reso is out sick and I have been
in a wedding all weekend as one of the
uh as one of our close friends was
getting married and we are the primarily
responsible party um and it is now 230
on a Sunday when this podcast was due on
a Thursday and I'm still showing up for
you guys hopefully that shows how much I
love you guys um so we're just going to
do a quick little solo episode this week
we're going to run through some research
and we're going to call it a week but I
had to give you guys something to listen
to right you know I I can't disappoint
my my listeners um so yeah and shout out
to the production team for dealing with
my my late uh Missing the deadlines
thanks Richard thanks Christian
appreciate you guys all right so let's
uh let's get into the research this week
we're going to cover four pieces of
research we're going to cover um Port
swigger sble roulette that they just
released we're going to cover three uh
Google reports that just got disclosed
uh with some cool attack vectors in them
and then finally we're going to wrap it
up with this nextjs corrupt middleware
research that just dropped a couple days
ago which is like crazy um all right let
me get some water let's jump into
it all right so first up let's look at
Samuel roulette this is once again an
awesome piece of research that was
released by the ports Wier research team
Gareth and um one of the other
researchers uh that who's listed around
here somewhere where is he Zach yep um
and this was unfortunately a research
collision with Alexander tan a hacker
one who I've mentioned several times on
the podcast who's kind of like the samel
god I've reached out to and said hey
could you like come on the Pod and they
said sure uh let me just get some cves
disclosed so if you're listening to this
Alexander now's your time man come on
let's go let's get on the pot um but I'm
definitely going to Ping him after this
one because it's uh it's pretty sick um
but yeah let's kind of go through this
specific attack this was a uh saml
bypass completely in Ruby saml affecting
gitlab unauthenticated uh account
takeover um and it was pretty awesome so
this type of attack comes from a
technique called roundtrip attacks and
I'll read this one line from the from
the right up here which describes it
pretty well samel libraries often parse
an XML document store it as a a string
and then later reparse it in Ruby samel
this process involves two different
parsers rexml which is used to parse the
document and validate the signature and
noid which is used to access uh
attributes and that should be sending
alarm Bells off in your head right right
because uh anytime there's sort of like
this double parsing environment then
there's chance there's a chance that
there will be discrepancies and that's
exactly what the ports sger research
team manipulated in the specific
environment so uh how did they do that
exactly well they came up with this
excellent payload which is being shared
on the screen for any of you who are
following Along on on YouTube but uh
this is a podcast so I will also say it
out loud um essentially What's Happening
Here is they present a uh XML document
that has a single quoted attribute uh in
it and this attribute contains uh an XML
comment and uh some entity uh entities
inside of it um and essentially what
what happens then is when this document
is parsed the first time the single
quoted attribute will be parsed as an
attribute but then when it's put you
know stored as a string like we said in
the first part that single qued
attribute becomes a double qued
attribute well that's a problem because
the first attribute uh had a double
quote in it so that would close the uh
double qued attribute that was being uh
converted from the single quote and then
allow you to specify uh
various other tags and comments and
stuff like that so what they did here is
they specified a comment and we're able
to insert a malicious assertion into the
assle response which then gets picked up
by the um the off engine later and used
to determine which user should be logged
in um so essentially what what they're
doing here is they're using attribute
manipulation they're using a double
quote or a single quoted attribute and
then when it's converted into a double
quote attribute it does something
different to the to the XML document um
very cool stuff there and it definitely
makes sense that that would be happening
when there's two different parsing
engines being used to uh affect the XML
there um so that's kind of the tldr of
the first part you can read uh more
thoroughly uh on the actual write up if
you'd like but the idea was double parse
the XML document and then have a
you know some data that is in a
attribute in the first time around that
is not in an attribute the second time
around allowing us to insert some
malicious XML but the attack gets a
little bit more difficult than that
because um of a couple factors one uh
you know they kind of want uh arbitrary
unauthenticated account takeover right
um but the way that this works is they
need to provide a uh a valid signature
for them to go through the first
signature check uh XML document parsing
right so they said you know in the
beginning let me see if I can find that
quote they said that uh this process
involves to do different parsers rexml
which is used to parse the document inv
validate signature and noid which is
used to access attributes okay so re in
order to get past that first one the
rexml they have to provide a valid
signature to their their samle response
endpoint right um and one of the ways
that they did that was super cool um is
that they used this metadata endpoint
that was associated with uh the
the XML environment let me see if I can
pull it up here um yes right here it
says finding a valid assigned XML
document can be challenging fortunately
the identif identity providers silently
provide a single sign on protocol WS
Federation by default for every tenant
WS Federation provides signed metadata
XML endpoints such as this and they link
to an XML endpoint so essentially what
they're able to do is hit this metadata
endpoint that is signed and then because
that has a valid signature on it they
can reuse that signature to pass bypass
that first part and then utilize the uh
attribute discrepancies to uh insert
their own um assertion into the the XML
document on the second parse through so
very creative attack vectors here the
other piece that I kind of wanted to
mention on this one that I kind of
skipped over for a second was how
exactly they got it to look at their
assertion versus the assertion uh that
was originally provided in the document
and the way that they did that was by
using something that I had never seen
before in XML let me see if I can find
here in the document yeah here it is
right here um which is a you know we we
all know about entities being defined in
in Doc type right that's how you do
traditional XML entity attacks um but
what I hadn't known is that you can
specify other types of uh objects as
well inside the doc type you can specify
um attributes entities and elements
right so those those three elements
attributes entities and if you think
about it that's kind of what makes up an
XML document uh or if you even think
about it from HTML which is sort of a a
tweak of XML you know you've got your
your your elements you've got your tags
right you've got the attributes for
those tags and then you've got these
entities right you know your dollar
dollar sign or your ersan sign and then
the entity and then the semicolon right
so it's cool that you can Define all all
three of those inside of the doc type
and it just when I was thinking about
this when I was researching it it kind
of made me realize a little bit more wow
okay I I kind of feel like I have a
better grip on XML now that I know what
this doc type is used for and it it's
being used to define these various
elements um so what they ended up doing
here was um they they looked at the the
way that uh nooi was checking for the uh
the signature piece uh I'm sorry not
nooi this is uh the the one that is uh
rexml searches for the signature element
and the way that it does that is that it
does a uh X path selector on a specific
uh attribute so it hits it looks for a
DS signature
and it looks for the uh DS attribute to
point to XML D Sig um so then what what
they did is they changed what uh what
assertion would have that um using that
uncommented out
uh attribute right so when the attribute
went from single quote to double quote
they applied a doc type ATT list which
is as opposed to a doc type entity they
they used the bang ATT list um Define to
Define a specific value for uh the xmlns
attribute on the signature block which
allowed them to sort of hijack um which
of the assertions or which signature
excuse me um should be looked at uh at
different times in the document so um
really really creative uh technique here
to take advantage of the fact that they
have the ability to modify the XML
document essentially after uh it's being
parsed using uh document types they use
that to insert a uh an attribute to a
specific signature that they that they
wanted um which was a really really
creative technique and so I kind of went
down the the um the rabbit hole a little
bit when I was researching this and
reading through it and you know I
figured out that there was elements
attributes and entities but then I also
found this really really weird um uh
image and I Christian I'm gonna I've got
it in the dock so just go ahead and put
that up on the screen the use of
elements versus attributes um there's
this picture that I that I took from the
docs that says apparently data can be
stored in a child element or in an
attribute so if you have something like
the example that they gave here was they
have a person tag in XML right and they
have sex equals female and then they've
got you know additional data about that
person such as their first name and last
name in The XML document and they close
off the person tag right so the the sex
for the person is defined in the
attribute and then they said this is an
equivalent document and they say person
uh close the tag and then inside that
there's another tag that has sex that
has first name that is last name and
then you close the person tag and
apparently you can use attributes and
sub elements interchangeably in XML
which I was like what that seems super
whack um so yeah anytime you have an
attribute on a tag you can also specify
that attribute as a subtag of the tag
that the attribute should have been on
which seems a little bit weird to me and
I'm sure there's weird out there
that uh you know takes advantage of that
fact so definitely check that out if
you're in XML um or XML confusions that
sort of thing um all right let me take a
look at my notes really quick here and
make sure I didn't forget about anything
else yeah I mean I would just say
everybody who is interested in XML you
should take a look at how Doc types work
I just read the WW or W3 schools um sort
of writeups on how they work and there's
some really interesting stuff in there
that isn't sort of surface level what
you would think about when you think
about doc types um so I definitely
recommend that all right so episode guys
so I I don't get the chance to take you
know a breather while while Joseph's
talking and I so I got to get my water
real quick before we move on to the next
one all right so this next write up um
that I kind of wanted to cover with you
guys let me give a little bit of context
to this so the Google um VP does have
disclosed reports but they don't get
disclosed very often and recently they
just kind of did a batch release of some
of the reports from 2024 so I kind of
went through and skimmed through each
one of them and tried to find the ones
that had the coolest attack vectors to
it um and I'll go ahead and kind of go
through those now with you guys and uh
and just kind of give you the tldr on
what you could take away from
those so this one right here is entitled
loophole of getting Google form
associated with Google Sheets with no
editor owner access so essentially um
this is a way for you to take the Google
sheet that is associated with a specific
um Google form right where it stores the
results from the Google form and get
that original URL uh for the form so you
can make more submissions and I just
thought that this was such an excellent
example of understanding how your
targets your targets security model and
your threat model works right um because
I think if you're not intimately
familiar with Google Drive and what you
should or what you should not be able to
see then you wouldn't wouldn't know that
you're not supposed to be able to get
the form associated with a given
spreadsheet that contains the results of
that form um so the researcher here Dove
really deep understood the threat model
really well and was rewarded with a
$7,500 Bounty for this finding um and
essentially what he did was he took the
the uh document ID from uh the the
resulting spreadsheet and he created
another spreadsheet and added an
appscript to
that excuse me my voice is getting a
little
raspy he um he took the document ID and
put it inside of a appscript function in
a spreadsheet that he does own and have
editor access on and used the
spreadsheet app. open by ID function to
open up the ID of the um spreadsheet
that he had read access on but not owner
and edit and called the get form URL
function on that specific um spreadsheet
and that returned the the form that the
user was not supposed to have access to
so I just thought that this was such an
awesome attack Vector scenario right
using this um app script language and
the functions in that language to test
and validate that they're implementing
the threat model surrounding who should
have access to what properties of a
Google sheet correctly um and I just
thought that was awesome and so he he
did that once here and got $7,500 for it
and then he did it one more time over
here um so was December 2024 and he got
$15,000 for this one which is nuts and
this one is very similar just does the
exact same flow flow grabs the um
document ID from the readon document and
then passes it into an appscript on a on
a document that he does own and calls
the get editors function to get a list
of people who have edit rights to the
specific document and apparently if you
have readon right to a document you
shouldn't be able to see the email
addresses uh and users uh information of
the other editors on the doc so this one
actually dumped back emails uh and and
stuff like that usernames um
which Google considers pretty valuable
information um and so this was a really
awesome find I just I love that model
and you know for any of you Google
hackers there I'm sure this guy went
through and totally milked all of this
and you should definitely not look for
any of the ones that he missed using
appscript and you should also definitely
not diff the appscript docs to make sure
when new functions are added that you
can't be abused to do something similar
I think that's probably a waste of time
because this guy definitely found
everything as all testers
do all right let's go ahead and move to
the next one oo little bit of water
popped out there and got on my
glasses all right let's go to the next
one um let's see right
here okay this was another write up uh
that actually only got $500 which I was
a little bit disappointed on um but I
kind of wanted to talk on it because it
was relevant to a uh sort of topic I
wanted to discuss with you all um so let
me first dive into it and and and then
tell you what's going to what's
happening so the title for this one is
cloud tools for Eclipse chaining
misconfigured oath call back redirection
with open redirect vulnerability to leak
Google oath token with full gcp
permissions which one sounds sick so uh
Mr Mo sakur that uh reported this you
rock um but essentially the tldr of this
one is with Google ooth in this specific
um environment you could redirect to to
uh a Lo Local Host essentially which is
something that we often see in uh awath
flows you that the either like a default
URI that is approved is any port on
Local Host um or you know specific
client IDs have start Local Host and on
any port you know opened up um as
available for redirect URI um and what
this guy did is he actually went and
found a product from Google that listens
on Port um on this port that was allowed
Port 880 and then found an open redirect
in that product and chained it together
right so they can't say like oh well if
you have Local Host uh you know access
to catch the the call back then you
already have the device owned or
whatever right they they they have to
take responsibility for their own tool
that was had an open redirect on that
specific uh URL in Port and then sort of
chain that all the way through um so I
thought that was brilliantly done by the
researcher here and it also made me
think of another attack vector that sort
of uh was recently came to my attention
with regards to Local Host redirects for
ooth uh callbacks and that is that when
you are on mobile on a mobile
device um you any app on that device can
listen to any port above 1,24 without
any additional permissions right so you
can just have an Android mobile app that
just binds to Port 880 and then gets a
call back from these specific uh oo uh
call backs that allow access to Port 880
or Local Host whatever Port right um and
I and so I had a friend recently that
pocked that out and submitted it to a
program and it got informative because
you were have an app on the device which
is just so dumb and I'm not going to
name and shame the program I'm going to
give them some time to like do their
thing but um yeah I was pretty
disappointed by that outcome because you
cannot just let every other app on the
device have access to your account right
like that's not okay um so I think that
this is a very valid attack vector and I
think that it was really easy
surprisingly easy with cursor and such
to Pock that um script that creates the
mobile app and uh catches the oath code
so definitely um something you guys want
to be on the lookout
for um all right so that was all I had
for the uh the Google writeups uh
definitely some cool ones there there
are some other good ones there I just
didn't decide they they just weren't as
broadly applicable to everybody um so I
grabbed those three just because I
thought they were like this is a really
cool um way to approach a target for the
first one and then you know obviously
the call back to Local Host stuff is
just really applicable to so many
programs all right last one guys and
then I'm going to go chill it is Sunday
um so I normally try to take Sunday
pretty chill but this week was crazy
with the wedding
so all right um this next piece of
research uh is by by zero webc zero with
an h z h r o maybe it's Z hero I don't
know kind of a cool name um but they uh
also did some research before I jump
into this one the nextjs and the corrupt
middleware they also did some other
research earlier this year that released
in January on um uh webcash stuff uh for
nextjs which actually I don't see in
their oh it's under their research tab
on their website yeah right here
so uh they they've been kind of poning
JavaScript based Frameworks for a little
while this is the one I was thinking of
right here nextjs cash and chains the
steel Elixir um so there's there's lots
of good research here if you're
interested in N or
nextjs uh so definitely go check that
out but this one in particular I thought
was hilarious because the payload is so
simple um so the researcher um kind of
went through the nextjs source code and
was looking at middleware and apparently
within the code of uh the nextjs
middleware there is this uh blob of code
that checks the x- middleware Das sub
request
header and if this header contains uh a
a specific string then it will just skip
all the middleware lovely right and the
reason that they created this was uh as
the researcher noted in the right up so
that there isn't like an infinite Loop
of middleware right if the middleware
sends a request to another you know
route on the application then it's not
just going to infinitely loop on the
middleware um so that's cool I I like
that uh but the way that they
implemented it was so funny it was like
okay x middleware sub request and then
the value for it is like the path of the
where the middleware lives uh which is
like extremely predictable in in this uh
next ja environment uh because at the
time of there was only like one router
that exists the pages router and your
middleware had to be placed underneath
that inore middleware um so th this
payload right here x middleware d sub
request uh with the value of pagesor
middleware was all you needed to bypass
any middleware which is often very often
where um authentication or authorization
checks are being
done um so that was a great find by the
researcher here uh and that this
specific uh exploit affects um versions
before 12.2 but there after 12.2 there's
a different exploit uh that is required
because of uh the the middleware code
getting moved around uh which is this
one with that in mind the payload for
the first version starting with version
uh 12.2 is very simple x middleware d
sub request colon middleware right just
super easy to tack on there and then uh
there's another variant where it could
be in the sources directory so Source
middleware um really awesome awesome
stuff that they that they have here they
built out all of the different paths
there are a couple edge cases as well
where you might need to repeat your
payload uh across different versions but
uh this I feel like is massively
exploitable in a bug Bounty environment
um and they did go through and and milk
it on some bug Bounty programs uh as
they said in the article um obviously
the the biggest impact would be you know
off bypass here and you can access some
routes that are should be protected but
they also mentioned that often times CSP
headers uh are implemented in middleware
so you can use it to bypass CSP and get
that version cached or you can do Doss
via cash poisoning as well um if there
is sort of a a rewrite that was
happening in the middleware for various
like location based stuff um and so
really really great finds here very
thorough um and yeah I think it's really
applicable to bug Bounty I think any of
you Recon boys out there uh that can do
Mass scanning may want to sort of look
for those uh 403 end points that are
coming back from uh nextjs middleware
and then try to tack on like a few
variants of the payloads that are in
this uh right up to to try to bypass off
in those environments um so all right I
think that's about all I had from the
research for this week let me see if
there's anything else we do have a fun
episode planned for next week when reso
gets feeling back better um so we'll
I'll save most of the stuff that I had
planned for that for the next time
around um I guess as I'm closing out
here I will say would love to to see all
of you guys in the critical thinking
Discord we've got a really awesome
community over there especially in the
critical thinkers um we've got some fun
master classes up we' got some hack
along scheduled um and then we've also
got the full-time Hunters Guild for any
of you guys who are doing this full-time
that's been particularly helpful for me
I've essentially said to Yugi who's uh
who's the community manager here at
critical thinking hey I want you to run
this and I'm going to be a member of the
full-time Hunter skills because that's
what I need and so I've just kind of
been chilling you know I'll I'll pop in
and do like the meet and greets and
stuff like that but I've mostly been
using the full-time Hunters Guild as
like an accountability thing for me and
collaborating with some of the other
hackers there and I can personally say
it's been really helpful so um for any
of you full-time Hunters that are
listening I would love to see you in
that definitely apply you can find the
application at cb. Showtime Hunters
Guild ftg right slash FG for fulltime
Hunters Guild um all right that's a wrap
on this week love you guys see you next
week and that's a wrap on this episode
of critical thinking thanks so much for
watching to the end y'all if you want
more critical thinking content uh or if
you want to support the show head over
to ctbb Dosh show/ Discord you can hop
in the community there's lots of great
high level hacking discussion happening
there on top of master classes hacks
exclusive content and a full-time Hunter
Guild if you're a full-time Hunter it's
a great time trust me all right I'll see
you there